searchtechstart.com 2019-04-20

# Search Services | Oath Policies

This policy describes our current privacy practices for the Oath Search and Assistants brands, websites, features, products, apps, software and other services (“Search Services”). All information that is collected, provided to Oath or stored in your Oath Account will be treated, used and protected in accordance with the Oath Privacy Policy. This information may change as Oath revises these Search Services by adding or removing features or using different service providers. Some features are only available if you are a registered user. Please visit [Help](https://help.yahoo.com/kb/index?page=product&y=PROD_SRCH&locale=en_US) if you have questions about these Search Services.

This page describes specific privacy practices with respect to [ Yahoo Search](https://search.yahoo.com/), Yahoo Assistants, Yahoo Local and Yahoo Shopping. Additional information is included for certain Search Services listed below.

### **Yahoo Search**

#### **Information Collection & Use Practices**

**Search**

  * When you conduct a search on a product or service that uses our search technology, we collect information from your experience, such as your search queries.
  * Search Assist helps you find what you are looking for by automatically offering popular search terms and new topics to consider. Search Assist may base suggestions on aggregated searches across all users and your individual search history.
  * The Yahoo Search History tool allows you to see what you've searched for in the past. [ Learn how to manage your Search History tool](https://help.yahoo.com/kb/index?page=content&y=PROD_SRCH&locale=en_US&id=SLN22645).
  * When you use Yahoo Search, you may see relevant, private results selected from other sources, such as your Yahoo Mail. Only you can see your private search results when you’re signed in. [Learn how to manage, including turning off, Private Results. ](https://help.yahoo.com/kb/search/SLN22585.html?impressions=true)
  * Some advertising you receive may be customized based on your searches or related terms at Oath. Please visit our  Opt-Out page to learn more about the information used to personalize your search experience. If you opt-out, you will continue to see ads Oath serves on these websites, but they won’t be customized to your interests or search history.
  * Visit the [ Search Preferences](https://search.yahoo.com/preferences/preferences?pref_done=https%3A%2F%2Fsearch.yahoo.com%2Fsearch%3Fp%3Dtest%26ei%3DUTF-8%26fr%3Dsfp&.bcrumb=152fFQ.8kx9&tmpl=&fr=sfp) page to manage your Yahoo Search experience, including Safe Search, Search History, and Private Results.
  * Yahoo Search uses image recognition algorithms to identify public figures, scenes, actions, or objects to make it easier to search images

**Search Partners**

  * A variety of third party providers help power Oath search and sponsored search services.
  * We may share your search query, IP address, and other depersonalized information from your web browser or app, such as a unique identifier for your web browser, with these search partners.
  * These third party providers may use this information, as well as your search results clicks, to provide more relevant advertising and search results, for search product improvement, research and analysis, and to help detect and defend against fraudulent activity on sponsored or contextual search results.
  * We may reformat results provided by these search partners to provide an enhanced search experience to you.
  * To learn more about the data collection and use practices by these search partners, please visit our  Third Parties page.

**Sponsored Search Results**

  * Search results may consist of sites that have paid for placement in the search results.  Learn more.
  * Search results may contain tracking URLs provided by Yahoo Search Marketing and/or our Search Partners to identify clicks from the search results page.

**Assistants**

  * Yahoo Assistants are a new category of products and services using artificial intelligence guided by humans. These include chat bots operating in messenger platforms, virtual personal assistants and stand-alone apps accessed on Oath or through third-party apps and services. Assistants may collection information about you in a manner different from other search technologies.
  * Yahoo Assistants may interact and converse with you to answer questions, help complete tasks or perform other activities. Assistants rely on our personnel and automated systems to respond to questions or instructions from users.
  * We may collect information about you when you use our Assistants, including your conversations and interactions with the Assistant, your Yahoo ID and information associated with your account.
  * We may also collect information provided by a third-party (including apps, messaging platforms and other services) interacting with our Assistants, which could include: your account information with the third-party, such as user ID, name, photo, phone number, email address; and device information such as device ID, device type, operating system, and mobile carrier.
  * Oath’s personnel and our automated systems may have access to all communications content as it is sent, received, and when it is stored, in order to fulfill your requests, further product and services development, and provide personalized experiences and advertising through Oath’s products and services.
  * When you are communicating with our Assistants through a third-party, please read that company’s privacy policy to better understand what information it may retain and for what purposes.
  * Location information collected through the Yahoo Assistants may not appear in the Location Management page.

**Other**

  * Users who are European residents can [ request](https://io.help.yahoo.com/contact/index?y=PROD_SRCH&token=w5FCchB1dWGbc2RE0kcjij0u65u86GoeqUkmqtTbcuO%252BLU%252FUQgc3BzwNZtXp6XEXn5YwJ6Wu6A9MCYnw7SzQy5BySKiGUpoj0xug9Sr7JfZdSQjOyA5v2Of2mZTMotlsehDS1xQqu1g%253D&locale=en_GB&page=contactform&selectedChannel=email-icon&isVip=false.) that certain URLs be blocked from search results in certain circumstances.

### **Yahoo Local**

#### **Information Collection and Use Practices  **

**My Local**

  * This feature allows the signed in user to store Business Listings by using the “Save” button on the Business Profile Page.
  * Signed-in users may also view their recently searched and recently viewed businesses.

#### **Information Sharing and Disclosure Practices**

**Reviews**

  * Your review will include your Yahoo ID or an alias or other account information you have made public and will link to your profile. Use the pull-down menu to choose the alias you would like to post with. You may also create a new alias and profile.
  * Currently it is not possible to edit your own review once it has been posted, however if you try to post a second review you will see your previous review which may then be resubmitted.
  * If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

#### **Practices Regarding Your Ability to Update or Delete Information**

  * Currently it is not possible to edit your own review once it has been posted, however if you try to post a second review you will see your previous review which may then be resubmitted.

### **Yahoo Shopping**

  * [Yahoo Shopping](http://shopping.yahoo.com/) allows you to access thousands of merchants and products in one place. To make a purchase from a merchant listed on Yahoo Shopping, you are not required to be a registered user.
  * [PriceGrabber](http://www.pricegrabber.com/) powers the functionality of Yahoo Shopping. For more information on how PriceGrabber collects and uses your information, please visit the PriceGrabber [ Privacy Policy](http://www.pricegrabber.com/privacy-policy).

#### **Information Collection and Use Practices**

**Purchases**

  * We may use your Yahoo Shopping queries and Yahoo Shopping browsing history to customize your experience and provide you ads that may be of more interest to you. We show you your Yahoo Shopping queries and Yahoo Shopping browsing history made within the past 60 days in the [ Recent Activity module](https://help.yahoo.com/kb/shopping/sln5102.html).
  * To disable Recent Activity, select “off” in the upper-right corner of the module. To clear your Yahoo Shopping browsing history, select “clear all” in the upper-right corner of the module. To learn more about your ability to opt-out of interest-based advertising, click  here. To learn more about how the Recent Activity module works, click [ here](https://help.yahoo.com/kb/shopping/sln5102.html) 
  * When you make a purchase from a merchant listed on Yahoo Shopping, the merchant will ask for information such as your name, billing and shipping addresses, email address, telephone number, and credit card information. Please refer to the privacy policy of each individual merchant to learn how they use and store your information.
  * Each merchant from whom you make a purchase will receive your personal and order information directly. Yahoo Shopping does not see, collect, store, or use this information in any way.
  * Each merchant is solely responsible for their use of your personal and order information.

**Comments**

  * When signed into the Yahoo Network you may comment on user reviews. When you comment, your profile is linked to that content and your display name and profile photo are visible to other users.
  * You must be a logged-in, registered user to post a comment.
  * Comments you post will be displayed publicly along with your Yahoo ID or chosen nickname and profile picture or avatar.
  * You may also delete a comment you have posted by selecting the ‘delete’ option next to the comment you wish to remove.
  * Your comments are visible to you on the “My Comments” tab next to the commenting streams.
